<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "module.dtd">

<module name="GROUP_11">
  <doc>
    <description>
      This module, developed by Group 11 for the AE4317 Autonomous Flight of Micro Air Vehicles course at TU Delft, 
      works in conjunction with a color filter (cv_detect_color_object), ground detection, and the guided mode of the autopilot. 
      The primary avoidance strategy of this module is to navigate the drone based on the ground visibility, which is determined 
      by analyzing the percentage of pixels (in three areas left straight and right) identified as ground in the drone's camera feed. 
      The ground color is initialized once the drone is airborne and in a safe state, based on a predefined area in the lower center 
      of the camera's view, where the ground is expected to be visible.

      In addition, the module employs a strategy to detect orange obstacles by counting the number of orange (specified as color_count) pixels in the camera's view. 
      If this count exceeds a certain threshold (specified by color_count_frac), it is assumed that there is an orange pole in the drone's path, 
      prompting the drone to maneuver away.

      Furthermore, this module monitors the presence of "green" (ground) pixels in the central lower area of the drone's view 
      (specified by floor_central_count). If the percentage of green pixels falls below a predetermined threshold, the module assumes 
      there is an obstacle ahead, triggering a turn to avoid collision.

      Additionally, the module includes a sky detection feature, which analyzes the number of green pixels within the sky's section of the 
      camera feed (quantified by plant_count). If this green pixel count exceeds a specified percentage threshold, it is inferred that there may 
      be a plant in what should be clear sky. Under such circumstances, the drone is programmed to execute a turn to avoid collision.

      To ensure the drone remains within the cyberzoo, our module measures the total green pixels (floor_count) in the camera's perspective. 
      When this count surpasses a specific threshold, the drone is considered to be nearing the cyber zoo's perimeter, prompting an automatic 
      turnaround to stay within boundaries.
    </description>
    <define name="ORANGE_AVOIDER_VISUAL_DETECTION_ID" value="ABI_BROADCAST" description="which VISUAL_DETECTION message to recieve for orange pole detection."/>
    <define name="FLOOR_VISUAL_DETECTION_ID" value="ABI_BROADCAST" description="which VISUAL_DETECTION message to recieve for floor detection."/>
    <define name="GROUND_CENTRAL_VISUAL_DETECTION_ID" value="ABI_BROADCAST" description="which VISUAL_DETECTION message to recieve for ground central detection."/>
    <define name="PLANT_VISUAL_DETECTION_ID" value="ABI_BROADCAST" description="which VISUAL_DETECTION message to recieve for plant detection."/>
  </doc>
  <settings>
    <dl_settings>
      <dl_settings name="GROUP_11">
         <dl_setting var="oag_color_count_frac" min="0" step="0.01" max="0.5"/>
         <dl_setting var="oag_floor_count_frac" min="0" step="0.01" max="0.5"/>
         <dl_setting var="oag_max_speed" min="0" step="0.1" max="1"/>
         <dl_setting var="oag_heading_rate" min="0" step="5" max="45" unit="rad" alt_unit="deg"/>
         <dl_setting var="oag_central_floor_frac" min="0" step="0.01" max="0.5"/>
         <dl_setting var="oag_plant_frac" min="0" step="0.01" max="1"/>
      </dl_settings>
    </dl_settings>
  </settings>
  <dep>
    <depends>cv_detect_color_object</depends>
  </dep>
  <header>
    <file name="GROUP_11.h"/>
  </header>
  <init fun="group_11_init()"/>
  <periodic fun="group_11_periodic()" freq="4"/>
  <makefile target="ap|nps">
    <file name="GROUP_11.c"/>
  </makefile>
</module>